# LOUISE FATTON

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



#### CONTACT

6

+41.78.778.70.38



louise.fatton@hotmail.fr



https://lfatton.github.io/portfolio



Fahys 7, 2000 Neuchâtel, Switzerland

#### EDUCATION

#### **42 CURSUS**

Computer Science 42 Paris 2018 — 2022

#### ERASMUS

English Language and Literature University of Leeds 2014 — 2015

#### **BACHELOR OF ARTS**

English Language and Literature & Japanese Studies University of Geneva 2012 — 2016

#### SKILLS

## | Technical

C / C# / C++ / Python3

MVC ASP.Net / SQL Server

HTML5 / Less / JavaScript / JQuery

SDL2 / PixiJS / Vue3

Git / CMake / Makefile / Unix

#### SUMMARY

Fast learning and passionate software developer with 3 years of experience working in an IT company, I also have been part of several graphical and game projects during my studies and free time. I mainly worked with small teams for non-working projects, thus gaining experience in various areas of development ranging from programing a raycasting engine to working on gameplays and HUDs.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **FULL-STACK DEVELOPER**

UDITIS S.A. | 2019-current

Uditis is a 22-year-old company specialising in digital technology based in Peseux, Neuchâtel. It offers web-based solutions and applications as well as IT support. Uditis joined Sequotech Group at the start of this year and currently has 65 employees.

- Started as an intern for 6 months, mainly helping improve their inhouse CMS and working solo on a projects management solution from scratch, before being offered a permanent position as a developer.
- Worked on several different projects of varying team size, ranging from 1 to 10 people.
- Currently working on 2 different projects in MVC ASP.Net, while also being part of a team that is dedicated to the CSEM (Swiss Center for Electronics and Microtechnology); maintaining their intranet, and developing new applications curtailed to their needs.

# FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPMENT

Absinthe&Basilic | 2019

Absinthe&Basilic was a restaurant based in Fleurier, Neuchâtel. It unfortunately closed after the COVID-19 lockdown.

- First experience with web development and interacting with clients.
- Developed a one-page website on WordPress, based on their models.

# PASSENGER SERVICE AGENT

Swissport International AG | 2015 — 2016

Swissport is one of the leading companies providing ground services to in airports.

- Student job during last year at the University of Geneva.
- Part of the section dedicated only to the low-cost airline EasyJet and worked mainly during the weekends and holidays.
- Mostly worked on the early shifts (from 4AM to 12.30PM) as I did not mind the change in rhythm and thought the people nicer in the mornings.

# LOUISE

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### SKILLS

#### | Spoken languages

French - Mother tongue

English - Fluent

Japanese, German - Basic knowledge

#### HOBBIES

# My first games

Pokémon Gold Version Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets, Game Boy Color Version

## **Currently playing**

Fastwards

Zelda Breath of the Wild

#### Spent a lot of time on

Skyrim

The Witcher 3

Oxygen Not Included

The Sims 4

# Fun with friends

Battleblock Theater

Animal Crossing New Horizons

Overcooked 2

#### Obsessed with

Stardew Valley •

Don't Starve

Horizon Games

Assassin's Creed Black Flag

# When not playing

Pole Dancing

Reading and cooking

#### MOST RELEVANT PROJECTS

#### SCOP

42 Project | Current

A 3D modelisation project in OpenGL and C++17, where a 3D object is displayed with a texture.

• Currently gaining OpenGL and shader experience.

#### DOOM-NUKEM

42 Project | 2019

The goal was to create a game engine in C based on a mix of Doom and Quake (Duke-Nukem) engines using raycasting. We had to make a map editor and a map to binary file compressor as well.

• Including my working career, this is the biggest and more complex project I have worked on, it took us approximately 6 months with a team of 4 people to make.

#### TROMBI

Epic Game Jam | 2021

Bullet hell game made using JavaScript and PixiJS. You play a tie, with a pattern taken from your webcam, trying to survive the working world.

• Made in 2 days with a team of 6 on the given theme 'corporate'.

#### MOONWALKER

Epic Game Jam | 2019

First jam game. Rhythmic rogue like game where you play a bird moving a moon up a mountain, developed in JavaScript and PixiJS.

• Made in 2 days with a team of 5 on the given theme 'death'.

#### FRACTOL

42 Project | 2018

A C graphical project calculating and rendering several fractals.

- Solo project with a lot of complex calculations involved.
- Good for learning code optimization and graphical rendering.

#### EXTRA

# ONE OF THE FOUNDING MEMBERS OF AU BÛCHER

An intersectional feminist collective created at the end of 2021. Since then, the collective has been part of various feminist events during this year and even organised a one-day festival for women and queer people last May.